Gireesha Shenoy

https://www.linkedin.com/in/gireeshas

+91-7760753646 gireesha21@gmail.com

Seeking Position As:

QA/Testing Lead- Mobility

More than 11 years of of IT experience with 6+ years in Mobility domain. Experience in leading and managing projects involving Mobile Application testing in different industry verticals like Retail, Entertainment, Media and Health-Care. Extensive hands on experience in Automation, User Interface testing, API level testing for Web-Services, Functional and Regression testing on iOS and Android. Currently working as Tesco HSC India Pvt Ltd – Managing multiple QA Projects in retail domain

iOS and Android Platform XCode, Interface Builder, Instruments Eclipse, Android SDK, DDMS SOAPUI, API and Web services Testing SDLC Project Management Xamarin SDK iOS and Android Automation: UI Automator, Perfecto Charles, BugSense, Leanplum, Omniture

Test Management
Agile Methodology
JIRA, TFS, GitHub, Jenkins
Calabash, Ruby, Java Script
Team Skill Development
Code Coverage: gcov
Device test management
Mobile web testing

Professional Experience

Tesco HSC Technology Expert Aug, 2011 - Present

- Defined test strategy, test plan and release checklist for iOS and Android application testing
- Involved in Functional, Regression and Release testing of consumer mobility apps.
- Created training plan for the team
- Defined Regression plan for Web-Service testing and rollout activities
- Hands on testing of Mobile Applications on iOS and Android platforms
- Automation mobile application using Calabash/Ruby, Perfecto and UIAutomator
- Debugging and error root cause analysis using tools such as XCode (For iOS), Organizer, Eclipse (For Android), Android SDK and DDMS, Xamarin SDK.
- Production error monitoring and root cause analysis using Analytics and tools like BugSense, Omniture, Google Analytics, Site Conf
- Analytics testing Omniture, BugSense and Google Analytics.
- Web-Services and API Testing Automation using SOAPUI
- Hands on experience in HTTP monitor / Reverse Proxy using Charles tool

Atimi Software Pvt Ltd (India) Senior QA 2007 - 2011

QA activities for various Mobile App rollout that included: HBO, ESPN, MacWorld, J&J, GigaOM and NYT Apps,

- Creating Test Plan, Test Strategy, Review Test Cases, Manage Defect Tracking tool, resource management
- Review Software Requirement Specification, wireframes and User Interface mocks co-ordinate with PM and customer in finalizing requirement
- Writing Test Cases based on Requirement and iOS User Interface Guidelines
- Creating and maintaining Quality Metrics: Traceability Metrics- Task v/s Requirement, Requirement v/s Test Cases, Defect Detection Efficiency
- Review and validate application based on iPhone User Interface Guidelines
- Functional Testing, Regression, Managing Test Execution and Release

Robosoft Technologies Pvt Ltd (India) Quality Engineer 2005 - 2007

Multiple Projects – on Mac OS X Desktop

- Writing Test Cases and execution of test plan
- Functional Testing of Desktop Application on Mac OS X (10.3.x and 10.4.x)
- Defect Reporting and defect regression
- Creating Training material and presentation for new hires

Nidhi Technologies Pvt Ltd (India) Test Engineer 2003 - 2005

Testing of Desktop Applications and Client-Server application.

- Writing Test Cases and execution of test plan
- Functional Testing of Desktop Applications
- Defect Reporting and defect regression

Education & Technical Skills

Dr.AIT, Bangalore, India, 2003 Bachelor of Engineering

Address

#115, 1st Floor, B Block, Meridean Garden Apartments, Cholanagar, RT Nagar, Bangalore 560032